Yongjun Rong

Cherry Hill, NJ, USA, 08003 (US Citizen) Email: rongyj@hotmail.com Tel: 856-408-4027 Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rongyongjun/, Github: https://github.com/rongyj

EDUCATION

Jun.,2006, Master of Computer Science, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, TX, USA Feb.,1996, Master of Engineering, Shanghai JiaoTong University, Shanghai, China Jul.,1991, Bachelor of Engineering, Changsha Railway University, Changsha, Hunan, China

SUMMARY:

A lead architect engineer with strong hands-on digital transformation experiences in finance industry to migrate on-premises legacy monolithic tightly coupled system to cloud-native Microservices loosely coupled system and refactor strong synchronous ACID relational data consistency system to asynchronous event driven architecture (EDA) eventual consistency system, designed and implemented Internet scale cloud-native and hybrid enterprise system for financial/insurance and tele-communication industries. A full stack lead software engineer with emerging technologies worked as lead architect engineer, lead developer, lead DevOps engineer, senior system/network engineer for Barclays, Oracle, Comcast, IBM and Sun with over 20 years professional experiences focusing on back-end distributed system architecture design and implementation, system/network administration, infrastructure automation/orchestration. A tech lead and player with excellent verbal and written communication skills engaged in small or large team with agile methodology. A hard worker, who will bring valuable experiences, knowledges/skills and expertises to the team's success, is looking for enterprise architect, technical architect, cloud infrastructure architect or tech lead opportunities within Metro Philadelphia area or allowing work remotely.

SKILLS:

- Enterprise Architecture for large Finance/Insurance/Telecommunication organization (Strategic technology Domain, Distributed system, Microservices, EDA, streaming processing, integration, message transportation, architecture handbook, ServiceFirst)
- Digital transformation architecture engineering from on-premises legacy monolithic tightly-coupled system to cloud-native distributed loosely-coupled system (AWS, JEE, SQL, NoSQL, Microservices, CAP, BASE, Clean Architecture)
- Cloud infrastructure Design, Implementation and Automation (AWS/GCP/Azure, EC2 Lambda, S3, RDS, DynamoDB, VPC, API Gateway, ELB, R53, PrivateLink, ECS/EKS, IAM, Docker, Terraform, Kubernete, Serverless, IaaC)
- Cloud/On-premises infrastructure DevOps/System/Networking administration Automation and Orchestration(AWS, Docker, Kubernete, Terraform, Chef/Puppet/Ansible, CI/CD, GIT, Maven/Gradle, Linux HA, SAN, Ruby/Python/Bash, Nexus/Artifactory, Jenkins/Bamboo)
- SaaS Enterprise Application (ERP/CRM/Accounting/HR) Integration (EAI) Architecture Design and Implementation (AWS, VPC Endpoints, PrivateLink, SOAP/REST, WSDL/XML/JSON,)
- Internet scale loosely-coupled high available/scalable enterprise Microservices system design, development and deployment (Java, SpringBoot, Istio, Node.js, lambda, Rest/JSON, CQRS, event sourcing, kafka, EDA)

HOBBIES

- Pingpong (ITTF Score around 1200)
- IoT or Robot programming (Have iRobot and MIPOSaur at home. Programming against iRobot create SDK and MIPOSaur SDK.)
- IOS/Andriod Apps Development (Developing a Chinese charater learning App)
- Playing with cutting-edge technologies (Docker, Go, Kafka, Kurbernets and Amazon Cloudformation, JavaScript, AngularJs, ReactiveJs, Node.js)

Yongjun Rong

WORK EXPERIENCE SUMMARY:

Employments	Major Accomplishments & Technologies
Jun.,2017 – Current Barclays	Delivery Lead for strategic distributed system technology domain Group-wide Cloud Adoption for Contact Center, Merchant Services and Fraud
Wilmington, DE,USA VP,Lead Architect Engineer	Microservices, CQRS, Event Store, Event Driven Architecture (EDA), Kafka/ActiveMQ/IBM MQ, Kafka Stream, SpringBoot, Docker, AWS(EC2/IAM/S3/ECS/ELB/Lambda/RDS/VPC/R53/Security/AutoScalingetc), Kubernete/Terraform/Puppet/Chef/Ansible, Git/Maven/Jenkins/Bamboo, Python/Ruby/Scala/Bash/Go, ELK/AppDynamic, DynamoDB/MongoDB/ElasticCache/Gridgain, Linux/Windows/AIX/Solaris, aPaaS/VMWare/Cytrix,
May, 2014 – June, 2017 Oracle Redwood, CA	Docker Swarm/Compose/Stack CD/CI Test Environment for Cloud SDK/APIs/Connectors Cloud Enterprise Applications Integration(EAI) connectivity SDK/API plugin framework for Oracle SOA Suite Oracle Fusion Applications (FA) Business Event/Message-Driven Connector Framework
(WFH@NJ),USA Lead Software Engineer	Java, SOA, Web Services, SOAP/WSDL, REST/JSON/XML, XSchema/XSD, DOM, WSDL4J, SDK, API, MVC, Docker, Cloud, Amazon EC2, NoSQL, GIT, Maven, Junit, SoapUI, IaaS, SaaS, AWS,
Oct. 2010 – Apr. 2014 Comcast T&P Philadelphia, PA,USA Senior Cloud DevOps/Infrastructure Automation Engineer	 AutoBuild System for Build/Release more than 200 Microservices projects with GIT/SVN/Maven Configuration management and deployment automation with Puppet and Capistrano Continuous Integration (CI) and Continuous Deployment (CD) with Bamboo and Jenkins Performance Monitoring System for Jetty, JVM, Linux and Splunk Secured FTP server with virtual users and admins users with complex access permissions BOM (Bill Of Materials) Administration and Management Application (BAMA) Enhancement and maintenance Two Steps bare-metal Linux bootstrap system for HP Servers Linux HA for Git Repo(Gerrit) and Maven Repo (Artifactory/Nexus) Servers Automation scripts and tools for DevOps CoreOS and Docker prototyping and testing SDLC process management and junior team member training and mentoring DevOps, Automation, Docker, CoreOS, Ruby, Ruby on Rails 3, Bash, SDLC, GIT, Maven, Jira/Confluence, Bamboo/Jekins/Hudson, Nexus/Artifactory, Gerrit, CI/CD, Performance Monitoring, Splunk, JMX, Capistrano,
	PXE/TFTP, DHCP, DNS, Cobbler, Centos, MySQL/PostgreSQL, NoSQL, Cassandra, RabbitMQ, JMS, LDAP, SSO, Metrics, Graphite, Agile, RPC, Cloud, Clustering, Linux HA, HAProxy, Pacemaker/Corrosync/Cman, SAN, GFS2, RAC, Volume Manager,
Nov. 2006 – Oct., 2010 Boomi Inc. Berwyn, PA,USA Senior Software Engineer	 Boomi On-Demand Business Integration Cloud Service Cloud Platform/Infrastructure Design and Implementation for Boomi On Demand Production Environment Desktop Accounting and ERP Enterprise Applications Integration (EAI) Amazon EC2 and S3 SOA HA Environment Setup Development, Build and Deployment Environment for QA, Staging and Production Environment Research virtualization technology and implement Virtual Machines using VMware server and workstation Java to C/C++, DLL, COM/COM+/DCOM/.NET Integration SaaS system integration SAP system integration
	Java, SOA, IaaS, PaaS, EAI, XML, XSD, JAXB, JavaScript, .NET, EC2, S3, EBS, REST, SOAP, WSDL, SaaS, SAP, BAPI, ABAP, MySQL/PostgreSQL, Maven, SVN, JVM, JVM GC Tuning, Apache Luncene, Apache Solr, VMWare, Cloud,
Jun., 2006 – Nov.,2006 Vantage learning Newtown, PA,USA Senior System Engineer Manager	 Large scale SOA e-learning system architecture design and blueprinting Large Data Center Design and Administration Sun SPARCStorage SSA Array 100 and Sybase SQL Server (10.x, 11.x) Data (DB schema, data and Stored-Procedure) Recovery Ecommerce Open Source Software installation and Configuration Resin Application Server Distributed Session Design and Setup Linux, Centos, SOA, Java, .NET, Network, VLAN, Router, Firewall, Load Balancer, SOAP/WSDL, MySQL/PostgreSQL, Struts, Disk Array, Fedora, Redhat Linux, LAMP, eCommerce, SQL,
May, 2002 – Jun.,22,2006 Computer Science, Texas Tech University Lubbock, Texas,USA	 Unix network System and Software routine maintenance Setup Veritas Netbackup System with RAID0/1/5 and Tape Library Setup LDAP, Kerberos KDC and Cross-Realm system Migrated email system from UNIX mail server to Windows Exchange Server
Senior Programmer/Analyst and Unix System Administrator	 Secured Postfix SMTP server with SASL Authentication and Verification Installed AIX 5.1 and configured NIM on IBM RS6000 (10x 7043-140 boxes and 1x 7024-E30 box) Deployed Globus Tookit3.2.1 (OGSA/OGSI) Grid Computing Environment on Solaris 9(3 boxes) and Linux (3 boxes) Setup Jumpstart Environment for Solaris 9 and Solaris 10 Designed and Implemented the Single Sign-On (SSO) for Unix and Windows Environments
	The Migration from NIS+ to LDAP for Solaris JAVA, C/C++, GCC, GNU Make, perl, LADP, NFS, SSO, Kerberos, SSL, SMTP, Email Sever and Client, Solaris, AIX, Mac OSX, Linux, Windows Server, PAM, RAID, SCSI, Veritas, TFTP, RARP/ARP, Bootparamd, DHCP, Postfix, PostgreSQL, NIS/NIS+,

Yongjun Rong

Aug.,2002 – Jun.,2006	Master Thesis: A Service Wrapping and Provisioning Framework for SOA
Computer Science, Texas	GIS Project: A Yield Mapping and Prediction Information Delivery System
Tech University	Independently finished practical course projects list
Lubbock, Texas,USA	Java, C/C++, GCC, Gnu Make, Linux, Linux Kernel, GIS, Ant, Struts, J2EE, UML2, MVC, Maven, PostGIS,
Master Student	PostgreSQL, Solaris,
Apr., 2000 – May, 2002	Java Message Service(JMS) Prototype Application
Technology Development	Remote Learning Management Platform (www.ambow.com)
Center, Sun Microsystem	Bao Steel B2B Website (www.bsteel.com)
(China) Co.,Ltd.	Project Management Tools
Beijing,P. R. China	Java, J2EE, JMS, EJB, Servlets, JDBC, Message-Driven Bean, LDAP, SQL, Weblogic, OOA/OOD, UML, MVC,
Senior Software Engineer	Oracle DBMS, Java IDL, RMI, CORBA, JNDI, Solaris, CVS, Ant,
Aug.,1998 – Apr.,2000	Credit Card Internet Online Payment System
IBM China Research and	Jiro/Jini-based Storage Management System
Development Lab	Handwriting Recognizing System
Beijing,P. R. China	
Software Engineer	Java, J2EE, C/C++, Servlets, WebSphere, SSL, JDBC, Windows NT, SAN, POS, JNI, DB2,
Apr.,1996 – Jul.,1997	System Engineer,IBM Service Center
North China Institute	Software Engineer, HUAXU Golden Card Co.Ltd.
(Taiji Computers	Large scale Network System Design and Administration
Corporation)	
Beijing,P. R. China	C/C++, Assembly, Network Design, Router, Switch, VLAN, AIX, Disk Array, SSA, RAID, Volume Manager, IC,
System/Network/Software	RIP/OSPF, Ciso IOS,
Engineer	
Jun., 1991 – Sep.,1993	CIMS and FMS CAPP/CAD/CAM manufacturing Automation application development
Yongji Electrical and	
Motor Factory	COLL AWACAD CADICAMICADD CIMCIPMC DOS
ShanXi Province,P. R. China	C/C++, AutoCAD, CAD/CAM/CAPP, CIMS/FMS, DOS,
Mechanical Engineer	

Yongjun Rong 3